<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Nguyen Blog</title>
    <link>http://mynguy.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My Nguyen Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 14:11:47 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://mynguy.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Serialization and Deserialization with Gradle: Serializing Sets of Movies</title>
      <link>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 14:11:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post4/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, I will provide an update on my serialization and deserialization Java project under the guidance of Dr. Bowring. During our recent meeting, I presented an upgraded version of the project, now utilizing Gradle for enhanced project management. Additionally, Dr. Bowring assigned me the task of serializing sets of movies, making the project more complex. We also focused on code refinement to improve readability. Furthermore, Dr. Bowring introduced me to JUnit testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Serialization and Deserialization in Java: A Movie Serialization Project</title>
      <link>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 22:11:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post3/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, I will share my experience working on a serialization and deserialization Java project assigned to me by Dr. Bowring. The project aimed to enhance my understanding of these processes and improve my coding skills. I chose to create a simple movie serialization project, where I serialized and deserialized movie objects containing information such as name, genre, and release date. Throughout the project, I encountered various challenges and sought to improve the code&amp;rsquo;s dynamism, organization, and user-friendliness based on Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embarking on a Journey into Computer Vision and Machine Learning</title>
      <link>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 19:28:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post2/</guid>
      <description>I recently had an initial meeting with a family friend who introduced a fascinating project idea that combines computer vision and machine learning. While my knowledge in the field of computer vision is limited, I felt a surge of anticipation at the prospect of diving into this realm and learning more.
Our first day together was dedicated to setting up our work environments, establishing meeting schedules, and determining the framework for our project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nurturing Growth: My First Meeting with Dr. Jim Bowring</title>
      <link>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 11:28:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post1/</guid>
      <description>Today marked a significant milestone in my development journey as I had the privilege of meeting Dr. Jim Bowring, the esteemed head of the Cyber Infrastructure Research and Development Lab for the Earth Sciences (CIRDLES.org). Under his guidance, I aspire to expand my knowledge of git commands, embrace coding best practices, and evolve as a proficient developer.
With the arrival of summer, I have resolved to document my learning process and track my progress through GitHub Pages, utilizing it as a platform to share my experiences and insights.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
