<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on My Nguyen Blog</title>
    <link>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on My Nguyen Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 22:04:03 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://mynguy.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Testing, Pull Requests, and Ruby</title>
      <link>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 22:04:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post10/</guid>
      <description>In my recent meeting with Dr. Bowring, we discussed the tasks assigned to me, which involve diving into software testing and contributing to the Cirdles Tripoli Project.
The Process:
My journey began by forking the Tripoli project and setting up the upstream and origin on my computer, allowing me to start contributing to the codebase. This experience was particularly thrilling as it marked my first attempt at making a pull request, a milestone in my development journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Testing with Dr. Bowring</title>
      <link>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 14:50:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post9/</guid>
      <description>In my initial Fall meeting with Dr. Bowring, we delved into the intriguing realm of software testing. The session commenced with an engaging testing assignment, challenging my ability to think creatively when crafting inputs and oracles for special test cases. This exercise revolved around a classic problem known as the &amp;ldquo;Triangle Problem,&amp;rdquo; where three input values determine whether a triangle is scalene, isosceles, or equilateral (as detailed in G. Myers&amp;rsquo; book from 1979).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Exciting Countdown to Graduation and Future Endeavors</title>
      <link>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 09:25:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post8/</guid>
      <description>As I approach my final semester at CofC, the anticipation of earning my first bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree fills me with immense pride and joy. This upcoming milestone not only signifies a personal achievement but also a momentous occasion that will undoubtedly make my family proud. Being the youngest and the last one in my family to reach this academic summit, I am thrilled to be a part of something truly significant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elevating User Experience: Latest Updates in the Gradle-Based Movie Application</title>
      <link>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 12:11:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post7/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m excited to share the recent enhancements and features I&amp;rsquo;ve integrated into the Gradle-based movie application. My continuous journey of refining the user experience has led me to implement several improvements, streamline the code structure, and introduce new functionalities. Let&amp;rsquo;s delve into the details of these exciting updates.
Javadocs: Recognizing the importance of clear documentation, I&amp;rsquo;ve integrated Javadocs into the project. This addition offers comprehensive documentation for classes, methods, and variables, aiding both developers and users in understanding the code&amp;rsquo;s functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the New Features of movieGradle: A Multi-Modular Movie Library Application</title>
      <link>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 16:40:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post6/</guid>
      <description>Today&amp;rsquo;s blog post brings an exciting update on my movieGradle project, a multi-modular movie library application focused on serialization and deserialization. Since my last blog update, I&amp;rsquo;ve been diligently working on creating a user-friendly GUI for the app. This involved adjusting my FXML files, utilizing Scenebuilder, and implementing various buttons and features in the code. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the breakdown of the latest features:
Serialization and Deserialization: The application now allows users to serialize their movie library data into both CSV and binary formats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey into Computer Vision and Machine Learning Part III</title>
      <link>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/cv3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 14:13:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/cv3/</guid>
      <description>It has been an eventful month since my last update on our computer vision and machine learning project. Our team has made significant progress, particularly in understanding and utilizing YOLOv8 to train and create powerful computer vision models. In this blog post, I will share the latest developments in our project, including our transition to Roboflow, a user-friendly software platform that has provided us with invaluable resources for training and deploying models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Multi-Modular Gradle-Based Application for Serialization and Deserialization</title>
      <link>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 10:07:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post5/</guid>
      <description>I am thrilled to share the progress of my latest project—a multi-modular Gradle-based movie application that focuses on serialization and deserialization. This project has reached an exciting milestone as I successfully created a graphical user interface (GUI) for the application. I have rebranded the project repository, now known as &amp;ldquo;movieGradle,&amp;rdquo; which can be found on my GitHub at github.com/mynguy. The project&amp;rsquo;s README provides comprehensive information about the application and its functionalities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing XML and Binary Serialization in Gradle-based Project</title>
      <link>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 14:11:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post4/</guid>
      <description>Today I had the opportunity to meet with Dr. Bowring to delve deeper into XML and binary serialization. Dr. Bowring provided invaluable guidance on how to structure the code by creating separate classes outside the main program. Additionally, we reviewed my JUnit testing for these new classes to ensure accuracy and identify any discrepancies. This blog post will walk you through our discussion and highlight the progress we made towards developing a multi-modular Gradle project for my movie class, paving the way for an exciting GUI application using JavaFX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Serialization and Deserialization with Gradle: Serializing Sets of Movies</title>
      <link>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 14:11:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post3/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, I will provide an update on my serialization and deserialization Java project under the guidance of Dr. Bowring. During our recent meeting, I presented an upgraded version of the project, now utilizing Gradle for enhanced project management. Additionally, Dr. Bowring assigned me the task of serializing sets of movies, making the project more complex. We also focused on code refinement to improve readability. Furthermore, Dr. Bowring introduced me to JUnit testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey into Computer Vision and Machine Learning Part II</title>
      <link>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/cv2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 20:15:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/cv2/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the second part of our ongoing journey into computer vision and machine learning. In this blog post, I am thrilled to provide an update on our progress in learning annotation techniques for creating segmentation masks in instance segmentation. Instance segmentation, which involves detecting object outlines, has been a central focus of our exploration. Over the past month, our dedicated team has been working together, utilizing CVAT as our annotation tool, to produce datasets enriched with segmentation masks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Serialization and Deserialization in Java: A Movie Serialization Project</title>
      <link>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 15:33:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post2/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, I will share my experience working on a serialization and deserialization Java project assigned to me by Dr. Bowring. The project aimed to enhance my understanding of these processes and improve my coding skills. I chose to create a simple movie serialization project, where I serialized and deserialized movie objects containing information such as name, genre, and release date. Throughout the project, I encountered various challenges and sought to improve the code’s dynamism, organization, and user-friendliness based on Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey into Computer Vision and Machine Learning Part I</title>
      <link>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/cv1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 19:28:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/cv1/</guid>
      <description>I recently had an initial meeting with a family friend who introduced a fascinating project idea that combines computer vision and machine learning. While my knowledge in the field of computer vision is limited, I felt a surge of anticipation at the prospect of diving into this realm and learning more.
Our first day together was dedicated to setting up our work environments, establishing meeting schedules, and determining the framework for our project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nurturing Growth: My First Meeting with Dr. Jim Bowring</title>
      <link>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 11:28:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mynguy.github.io/posts/post1/</guid>
      <description>Today marked a significant milestone in my development journey as I had the privilege of meeting Dr. Jim Bowring, the esteemed head of the Cyber Infrastructure Research and Development Lab for the Earth Sciences (CIRDLES.org). Under his guidance, I aspire to expand my knowledge of git commands, embrace coding best practices, and evolve as a proficient developer.
With the arrival of summer, I have resolved to document my learning process and track my progress through GitHub Pages, utilizing it as a platform to share my experiences and insights.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
